Hello everyone and welcome to
English part, my name is Marco.
My name is Katherine
and today we're talking
about a very, well it's pretty
important part of your child's education.
That's right, something that many schools
do is they have a conference between the
teacher and the parent, so you know
they can talk about how the child is doing.
That's right, so this
is something very
common in American
schools and it's important
to learn some of the
words that you will hear.
So let's take a listen to our dialogue and
when we come back we'll be talking about
some of these words and phrases mean.
Thank you for coming tonight Mr. Weber.
As a teacher it's
great seeing the kids'
parents assist our parent
teacher conference night.
Of course, I'm very
interested to know how
my child is doing and also gets some
insight from you as to how he can improve.
Well, Allen is a great
student, he's a hard
worker and very well behaved,
however he does struggle a bit with math.
I guess he gets that from me.
I never did well in math when I was a kid.
What can I do at home to compliment
what he is learning in the classroom?
Well, it's important
that you sit with him
and review his homework
assignments and help him with math.
I would also recommend he stay after
school twice a week for tutoring sessions.
It will really help a lot.
Thanks a lot.
I will definitely do that.
Is there anything else?
Yes.
Here's a notice from
our financial department.
Seems your child's tuition is overdue.
Oh yes, I...
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a look
at some language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
First up in language
takeaway, we have the key
phrase here, which is
parent teacher conference.
That's right.
It's a parent teacher
conference and it's
basically a meeting
between the parent of the
child and the teacher of the child and they
talk about how well he is doing or she is
doing or where she needs
or he needs to improve.
That's right.
So this is something that
can happen maybe twice
a year, maybe four
times a year, it depends
on the school, but it's
just a meeting between
the parents or parents of the
child and his or her teacher.
That's right.
So it's very common
with schools in order to
make sure that the
parent knows how the child
is doing in school and
can improve maybe.
And one of the goals
is to ride the parent
with insight into how to
help the child learn more.
Okay, so insight is kind of like a
better understanding of things.
More clear picture, yeah.
So I could say, you know what Marco, I just
don't get that woman Cindy, can you provide
some insight into why
she made that decision?
That's right.
So you want some more
information or some type
of explanation as to why
she made that decision?
Exactly.
And so the teacher
will then provide this
insight by describing what he
or she thinks about the student.
That's right.
And well, the teacher
went on to say that Alan
is a great student, hard
worker, very well behaved.
So he is a hard
worker, that means he is
this, it's not an
adjective, this is now, he
is a hard worker, she is a hard
worker, he is very well behaved.
Now this is a way to describe him,
he is not naughty, he is well behaved.
That means he doesn't start fights, he
doesn't talk in class, he doesn't cheat.
Okay, so what would be the opposite?
You say a child or a person is well
behaved, what would be the opposite?
I would say the child who is
not well behaved is naughty.
Okay, so you say he is not well
behaved or just he is naughty.
He's very naughty, he
always starts fights in class.
Okay.
Now, the student is having a
little bit of problems with math.
And so the parent
asks what he can do to
complement what he is
learning in the classroom.
Okay, so to complement,
you might have heard
this verb before, but
here it means something
special, it means to add to, all right.
So, okay, the boy
Allen, he's learning a lot
in school, but maybe
he's not learning enough
because his math scores
just aren't good enough.
So the father wants to know
what can he do in addition
to school, what can he
do extra to help his boy?
So that will, it will
complement his studies.
That's right.
So we have to complement
someone as to say, oh
you look nice today,
or this in this situation,
this verb we are saying to provide
more support or extra help to something.
That's right.
So I feel really good
about accounting, but I
want to take an extra
math class to complement
my accounting studies because I'm
just not very confident in my math.
Very good.
Exactly.
All right.
So, and towards the
end, well, we're talking
about how the child's
tuition is overdue.
The teacher says the
child's tuition is overdue.
What is tuition Marco?
Well the tuition is the fees
that you have to pay for school.
Okay, so maybe a
private school will have a
tuition, so high school
or an elementary school,
but you often hear this in
regards to college or university.
So college tuition in
America are very expensive.
That's right.
And when a tuition is
overdue, it means that
it hasn't been paid yet
and so the payment is late.
The payment is late now.
A lot of things can be
overdue that means they
pass their due date
a bill can be overdue.
That's right.
So you should have paid your
bill already, but you haven't.
That's right.
So it's overdue.
Okay.
So a lot of vocab there.
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again.
Thank you for coming tonight, Mr. Weber.
As a teacher, it's
great seeing the kids
parents assist our parent
teacher conference night.
Of course.
I'm very interested to know
how my child is doing and
also get some insight from
you as to how he can improve.
Well, Alan is a great student.
He's a hard worker and very well behaved.
However, he does struggle a bit with math.
I guess he gets that from me.
I never did well in math when I was a kid.
What can I do at home to complement
what he is learning in the classroom?
Well, it's important
that you sit with him
and review his homework
assignments and help him with math.
I would also recommend he stay after
school twice a week for tutoring sessions.
It will really help a lot.
Thanks.
A lot.
I will definitely do that.
Is there anything else?
Yes.
Here's a notice from
our financial department.
Seems your child's tuition is overdue.
Oh, yes.
I.
All right, we're back.
So now we've prepared three key
phrases for you on fluency builder.
All right, the first phrase here on
fluency builder is to struggle with.
So Alan is a great student,
but he does struggle with math.
That's right.
So to struggle with something
means that you are having a hard time.
It's difficult for you.
It is difficult.
So when I was a student in elementary
school, I struggled with science.
Is there anything you
struggled with, Marco?
I struggled with.
I struggled a little
bit with history and
doing so for Marco,
history was hard for me.
Science was hard.
But you can also use
it for your work, right?
You can say, I'm
struggling a little bit at work.
I'm struggling with my new schedule.
I have too much to do.
Okay.
So after the teacher
said that Alan is
struggling with math, the parent actually
said, I guess he gets that from me.
I never did well in math when I was a kid.
So what is the parent saying?
He gets that from me
or she gets that from me.
This means that the child has
the same problems the parent has.
So when the parent was little,
he had a hard time with math.
He struggled with math.
And now his child struggles with math.
So it's something that maybe he
inherited or he got from his father.
He gets that from me.
So sometimes you will
hear that maybe somebody
is stubborn and you say, well,
you know, I get that from my dad.
Yes, I'm very talkative.
I get that from my mother.
That means my mother is talkative
and I have the same characteristic.
So we're basically
saying that you kind of
genetically inherit the
same characteristics.
Exactly.
All right.
And the teacher said
that, well, in order to
improve, Alan should
attend tutoring sessions.
Tutoring sessions.
This is important.
You might have heard the word tutor before
I have a math tutor, but a tutoring session
is actually the time
you spend together with
your tutor practicing
something or studying something.
Right.
So you don't have a class with your tutor.
You have a tutoring session.
That's right.
Class is for a teacher and many students,
but a tutoring session is one on one.
It's two people together, a
tutor and a student, a learner.
So the word tutor can be a noun.
You have a tutor,
which is a person that
helps you, or you can tutor someone
to tutor, which means to teach or to help.
That's right.
So in college, I had a tutoring session
with a math tutor two times a week.
That means my math tutor helped me
learn math outside of school after school.
Very good.
All right.
So a lot of great stuff there.
Listen to the dialogue one last time.
Thank you for coming tonight, Mr. Webber.
As a teacher, it's
great seeing the kids
parents assist our parent
teacher conference night.
Of course, I'm very
interested to know how
my child is doing and also gets some
insight from you as to how he can improve.
Well, Alan is a great student.
He's a hard worker and very well behaved.
However, he does struggle a bit with math.
I guess he gets that from me.
I never did well in math when I was a kid.
What can I do at home to complement
what he is learning in the classroom?
Well, it's important
that you sit with him
and review his homework
assignments and help him with math.
I would also recommend he stay after
school twice a week for tutoring sessions.
It will really help a lot.
Thanks a lot.
I will definitely do that.
Is there anything else?
Yes.
Here's a notice from
our financial department.
Seems your child's tuition is overdue.
Oh, yes, I.
All right, so parent teacher conferences, a
very common thing, a very common thing.
And I think sometimes
even a little bit scary
for the kid because,
you know, your parent
is going to go talk to
your teacher and maybe
your teacher's not going to
say great things about you.
Yeah, this is always
very nerve wracking for
children because
maybe he didn't tell your
mom and dad what you
got on your test in science
last week and then
your teacher will tell
your parents and your
parents will be angry.
Right.
So this is the time when the
parents can be honest with
the teacher and the teacher
can be honest with the parents.
That's right, because
sometimes teachers
will have a file with maybe your test scores
and they will show them to your parents.
So not only what
you get on your report
cards, but then you
actually see the tests and
it could be like you say
a little nerve wracking.
I've also heard though
it can be nerve wracking
for the teacher because
sometimes teachers
have to tell parents things that they
don't really want to know about their kids.
Right.
If the teacher says,
hey, your boy Alan, he's
not very good at math, maybe Alan's dad gets
angry and says, yo, no, that's not true.
He's very good at math.
Right, right.
So it can be hard for everyone, but I
think generally they're very positive.
They really help the students.
Right.
Well, it's interesting
and actually I haven't
really seen parent
teacher conferences to
be that common outside
of the United States.
So maybe if you're a
parent, you have attended
a parent teacher
conference or maybe when
you're a kid, your parents went
to your parent teacher conference.
And if you don't have
teacher conference,
parent teacher conferences in
your country, what do you have?
How do parents and teachers talk?
Let us know our website is EnglishPod.com.
All right.
We'll see you guys there.
Bye.
(upbeat music)